Speaker 1: What makes a free person versus a slave? A slave does not own his economic output. It belongs to the master. And even a serf, you could say, is beholden to the Lord. But even serfs got to keep 75% of what they produced. That's more than the average American. And the average American is lower in status than a serf.
Speaker 1: Most Americans would have to aspire to raise to the level of a serf. But again, the difference between being a slave and being a free person is owning the fruits of your labor. Well, if the government claims that it owns our labor, then what? We're all slaves to the government?
Well, I hate
Speaker 1: to
Speaker 2: say I told
you so, but
Speaker 3: I told you
Speaker 1: so. So...
Speaker 1: The peace deal with Iran is off and the war is back on. Donald Trump says the ceasefire is gone and the bombs are going to start to drop, I guess, tonight. And, you know, when I first talked about this so-called peace deal and the MOU upon which it was based, I said it was much ado about nothing. The markets were all excited about the end of the war.
But
Speaker 1: to me, it just seemed like a stall tactic because there was nothing really in this MOU. It didn't really have any teeth. There was nothing binding. It was really just a deal to try to make a deal, which they had without the memorandum. But the important part of the memorandum was that during this so-called 60-day
deal,
Speaker 1: ceasefire, that the bombs would stop and the Strait of Hormuz would open up, which was really the reason that Trump agreed to this deal or a deal to make a deal. It was to open up the Strait and to get the oil price down, which worked. Oil prices dropped. They were above $90 a barrel and they dropped to below $70 a barrel on the fact that
the
Speaker 1: strait was opening up, although it never fully opened to the degree that it was open before the war, but at least there was some movement of ships. And in fact, Donald Trump talked about why he needed to do it. And he said that maybe we
Speaker 4: were within two weeks away of running out of oil or something like that, and that had he not found a way to end the war,
Speaker 4: that he risked being the next Herbert Hoover because he was going to preside over a depression. So in other words, we were weeks away from a depression unless Trump found a way out of the war, which is not exactly something you want to acknowledge to your adversaries if you're negotiating, because if you want to negotiate, you want to do it from strength.
Speaker 4: not from desperation. Because if you tell the Iranians, if you just hold on for a couple more weeks,
Speaker 1: it's a depression. That gives them a lot of leverage to hold on. And in fact, I commented on the terms of the deal. And from my perspective, it seemed like Iran walked away the winner because they got all kinds of economic concessions. There was this
Speaker 1: fund, you know, a couple hundred billion dollar fund, whatever it was, to invest in Iran. They were getting sanctions lifted. They were going to be
able to
Speaker 1: sell their oil. And the only thing they were really agreeing to was not to develop nuclear weapons, which is something they had always agreed to. And in fact, Trump even acknowledged in interviews subsequent to the signing of the MOU that
Speaker 5: the
It
Speaker 5: would be unfair to tell Iran that you can't have nuclear power, that you can't enrich uranium for the purpose of generating nuclear power because it wouldn't be fair because everybody else has nuclear
Speaker 4: power. So all of a sudden we can trust the Iranians with nuclear power and even on missiles. Prior to the war, one of the objectives was to completely disarm Iran so they had no more missiles.
But
Speaker 4: then Trump said, well, how can they have no missiles? Other countries have missiles. They need to have some. So Trump seemed to back away from everything that he had been demanding just to kind of create a phony victory out of what
Speaker 1: amounted to defeat. But even that didn't even stick. We couldn't even make that phony victory
Speaker 5: last because it's already off.
And
Speaker 5: now Donald Trump is saying, well, I don't even think I need a deal anymore. I can't make a deal. So I'm not really sure what the status is or what they're going to do. But the piece is already off and we're back at war. Now, the markets reacted to this. The stock market was down. You know, I think the lowest or the biggest
Speaker 6: drop I saw was maybe over 700 points in the Dow. I don't know if we were ever down 800 points.
The
Speaker 6: Nasdaq was down, I think, a percent, percent and a half, but the Nasdaq managed to finish the day positive. I think it was the only stock market index that ended up positive on the day. In fact, I think the reason that money is going in to the Nasdaq is just a few tech stocks, the big AI hyperscalers. This is all that's working. It's the only trade that's actually still going, momentum trade. And so everybody is kind of piling in.
Speaker 6: it's almost as if the tech trade is the new safe haven. So the Dow was down over 1% today, about 570 points. Small caps were down about 1%. You know, gold was down. You know, gold continues to react to war news, escalation of war, as if it's bad news. And at one point, I think gold was down 2%.
Speaker 6: maybe 70 to 80 bucks at the lows but it didn't get below 4,000 so 4,000 is holding gold recouped a lot of its losses to close down just about 30 at 40 and 74 cents silver also down on the day but holding now no um close at 58 and 13 cents down a dollar 71 and
Speaker 6: But it's not, you know, it wasn't on four or five bucks. So I think silver and gold are holding in to support levels. And I think we're getting close to an inflection point where Warren News stops being bearish for gold and silver and starts being bullish because it is bullish. The markets just don't seem to get that.
Speaker 6: But the
Speaker 7: uncertainty surrounding war is bullish. But more important, it's all the extra money that we print, all the inflation that we create. And I'm not just talking about oil prices
Speaker 6: going up. And oil prices did rebound. And in fact, I think they're headed a lot higher. Right now, they closed the day up about 6%, just below $75 a barrel. But I think that this rally is going to have bigger legs.
Speaker 6: I think
Speaker 5: it's gonna be pretty clear to oil traders that no matter what happens, this
Speaker 4: war is not really ending and the straits not really reopening. Maybe it won't be shut airtight.
Maybe a
Speaker 4: few ships may be able to come through, but not nearly as many as used to come through. In fact, ironically, it seems to me that our main goal right now is just to restore the status quo. That would be a win.
Speaker 4: just to return the Gulf to the situation it was in before the war started. That's like the best we can hope for. Only even if we achieve that, it's going to be at a massive
Speaker 5: cost because I think oil prices will still be much higher as a result of what happened. But more significantly, and not just the loss of lives and the loss of property, and there was a lot of property lost, not just in Iran. We lost our bases in the Gulf. We
Speaker 4: lost property too.
Speaker 4: But the money, the money that we have spent on the war, that we are continuing to spend on the war, and if we ever get a peace, that's gonna cost too. We're gonna be spending a lot more money. I'm even reading now official estimates that the Iran war is gonna cost over $1 trillion. And again,
I said
Speaker 4: this on day one, forgetting about this peace
deal.
The
Speaker 4: day that
Speaker 5: Trump decided to declare war on Iran without Congress, and I criticize that as an undeclared, unconstitutional war, had Biden done this, the Republicans would have been saying the same thing. But because it was Trump, you know, the Republicans didn't care.
Most of
Speaker 5: them, anyway. I mean, Rand Paul, you know, made a big deal about Thomas Massey and now see what happened to him. Right. His seat is gone. All
right.
Apart
Speaker 5: from the constitutional aspects of it, when this war started and Trump was talking about how quickly it was going to be over, how we were going to kick Iran's ass, we had the greatest military in the world, thanks to him that he had built up this great military and that we were going to make short work of Iran, it was going to be liberation in Iran, just like we had a liberation day in Iran.
Speaker 5: He was gonna liberate the Iranians from their corrupt
Speaker 7: government. It was gonna be a total regime change. And all this was we accomplished,
you know,
Speaker 7: just in a few days. Well, we accomplished nothing in several months and we've given up on all those objectives. I mean, for all the talk of regime change, the regime hasn't changed at all. If anything, it's probably hardened. It's probably the same regime or it is the same regime. It's probably just more radical.
And,
Speaker 7: you know, for people who may think, well, at least we diminished the terrorist threat. I doubt it. We probably, you know, augmented it. We probably made a lot more enemies in Iran
Speaker 5: than we had before. And now, you know, it'll be easier for the terrorist groups to recruit people, you know, to to come after us somehow because of, you know, the lives that were lost in Iran as a result of the war that we decided to.
to
Speaker 5: start we didn't have to start it we just did but now we have to figure out a way out and i think the iranians know uh they've got us caught between iraq and a hard place but i said from the beginning this was going to be a quagmire just like iraq or just like afghanistan every time we go into the middle east we can't get out and trump recognized this at least you
And
Speaker 5: when he ran for office for a second term, it was the same thing. No more wars, no forever wars, stay out of the Middle East. And what do you know, you know, right in there. And in so doing, he ended up
Speaker 7: losing a lot of his supporters.
Speaker 7: Maybe he should have lost based on the economic policies, you know, the big, beautiful bill and the massive deficit spending
Speaker 5: associated with that, the tariffs. I'm going to talk a little bit more in this podcast about the tariffs when we get into the horrific trade data.
that
Speaker 5: came out this week. The tariffs were supposed to solve that problem, but the problem continues to get worse. But I want
Speaker 4: to continue to focus on the markets and the
Speaker 7: reaction to the war. The dollar did move up, but not very much. And I think the big story here is how little the
dollar rose
Speaker 7: in response to the re-escalation of the war. I mean, we're barely above 101 on the dollar index, so not getting a big bid. But what's the most significant, I think, is the action in the Treasury bond market because bond yields are almost at new highs for the cycle. If you look at where the yields closed on the
Speaker 4: 10-year Treasury,
Speaker 4: We're at 4.58,
Speaker 1: almost 4.6%. And the 30-year is at 507. Now, these are the yields that we had when
oil was
Speaker 1: about $100 a barrel.
So
Speaker 1: oil has a long way to go to get back up to the highs, and I think it will get back up to the highs. And oil and bonds were highly
Speaker 4: correlated. Bond yields and oil prices were rising together. Well, here, oil has only recovered to $75, and bond yields are already at the highs. And what that suggests to me is that when we see oil prices hitting new highs,
Speaker 4: bond market is going to be much higher than it was before, and that has substantial negative consequences for the US economy, for the housing market. The stock market is just whistling past this interest rate graveyard, not appreciating this, and piling into these tech stocks as if
Debt
Speaker 4: and interest rates don't matter to these companies when they matter big now because they're borrowing so much money to build out the AI infrastructure. They are taking on tremendous amounts of debt and the payback on these investments, if there ever is a payback, is into the future. And so you have to discount the present value of that future return and interest rates are very relevant to that factor.
Speaker 4: And in fact, the FOMC minutes came out today. And that also
Speaker 1: should have given equity traders a cause for concern. But again, they seem to dismiss the implications of those minutes. I'm going to get into those minutes on the other side of this break. So stick around. We're coming right back.
Speaker 8: There's a lot I should be doing for my health, but hydration is one of the few things that makes an instant difference. When I'm staying on top of it, I feel better, I have more energy, and I'm just more ready for the day. Drip Drop has made it easier to stay hydrated because it tastes great, works fast, and I can bring it with me wherever I go. It's doctor-developed, proven fast hydration because hydration isn't just something you do when you're behind. It's how you stay ahead.
Speaker 8: Drip Drop uses science-based formulas for rapid hydration so you feel results fast while getting three times the electrolytes of leading sports drinks. Drip Drop is trusted by firefighters, medical professionals, and over 90% of top college and pro sports teams because it's built to hydrate you faster and more effectively.
Speaker 8: than water alone. Perfect for staying active all summer long. Drip Drops Zero Sugar Plus is a breakthrough, fast-absorbing formula with an advanced blend of six key electrolytes, 15 essential vitamins and nutrients, and no sugar or artificial sweeteners. It's fast hydration built with what matters most. And honestly, all of their products
Speaker 8: tastes amazing. There are 16 original flavors and eight zero sugar plus options. I love the Cherry Limeade. And Drip Drop is a daily routine product, not just for workouts. To make it easy, Drip Drop has flexible subscription options. So you're never stuck without proven fast hydration. Right now, Drip Drop is offering podcast listeners 20% off your first order. Go to dripdrop.com
Speaker 8: and use promo code GOLD. That's dripdrop.com, promo code GOLD for 20% off. All right, so we got the
Speaker 1: release of the most recent FOMC, Federal Open Market Committee meetings. And look, the most significant aspect of this meeting, and this is the first meeting with Warsh as a Fed chair. And remember, Powell is still sitting in on this meeting. He's just no longer chairing it, but he's there.
Speaker 1: And so back in March, when Powell was still leading the committee, not a single FOMC member was expecting a rate hike this year, right? They were still talking about rate cuts. Now, fast forward
Speaker 4: days, and now nine, nine of the FOMC members, I think there's 13 total, right?
Speaker 4: nine of them see a rate hike this year nine that none of these nine saw three months ago it's the same economy i mean how could things be so radically different
Speaker 1: um that three months ago there was no sign of rate hike by these same these nine guys and now all of a sudden yeah we see rate hikes
The
Speaker 1: data didn't get that much
Speaker 4: worse. I mean, if you don't know what's going to happen or where rates should be, and then three months later, you have a completely different opinion, this is all nonsense. This is all a charade. In fact, one guy who saw no rate hikes, I don't know if it was a guy or a gal, but one of the FOMC members
who had no
Speaker 5: rate hikes now has three rate hikes.
Speaker 5: between now and the end of the year.
So
Speaker 1: he went from zero rate hikes to three in the space of a meeting. Now, to me, this is probably all theatrics because now we have a new Fed chair
who is trying to
Speaker 1: be hawkish, right? He's trying to pretend that he's hawkish by talking. And
in
Speaker 4: fact, several of these FOMC members did indicate that they wanted a rate
hike.
At the
Speaker 4: June meeting, but they decided not to, but they talked about it. They thought that maybe it was appropriate, but they weren't in the majority. And so they, you know, unanimously decided to wait. But I think that the FOMC under Walsh is now trying to deliberately create the impression that they're that they're now got their inflation fighting chops and that they're independent from the
the
Speaker 4: president, because the president has made it clear he wants lower interest rates. But the Fed is trying to maintain its independence, and at least they know that they can be independent now without incurring the immediate wrath of the president. Because in the past, the president was very vocal in his criticism of the Fed.
Speaker 4: under Powell,
Speaker 5: specifically Powell, but also, you know, Lisa Cook trying to, you know, find a way to go after her. But I think the FOMC was concerned about that. They know that Walsh has a honeymoon,
Speaker 4: that there's going to be some time before Trump is,
Speaker 4: can actually come out and speak critical of Walsh because he just spoke, you know, so flattery how great this guy is, you know, central casting, ordered him up his standard line. But he just picked Walsh, right? He has a lot of confidence in him. And he said, hey, whatever he decides, he decides. So the Fed has a lot more room now to at least talk tough.
to
Speaker 4: pretend to be tough, knowing that Trump is sidelined from speaking critical.
So I
Speaker 4: think that that's what's going on here. I still don't believe that the FOMC actually intends to hike rates. These are the same guys that three months ago didn't think there'd be any rate hikes. Of course, three months ago, rate hikes were justified.
Speaker 4: they're still justified but they were justified back then too inflation was much too high back then it was obvious and in fact if you go and read the FOMC minutes everybody was concerned that inflation is still too high it's been too high for five years so why why did they cut rates in the first place given where inflation was
and
Speaker 4: Interestingly enough, though, even though everybody is concerned that inflation is too high, they all still think it's going to come back down to 2%. So they all still believe that their monetary policy is going to work. Even if it's taking longer than they thought, they still believe that ultimately, based on the policy we have now, that inflation is going to return to 2%. They just don't know when.
Speaker 4: but they have confidence that it will. But I don't know where that confidence is coming from. And in fact, they actually blamed inflation. If you look at the minutes, there were two kind of excuses for why inflation is high. One was the
Speaker 5: tariffs, right? So that's an excuse that they could keep on using, blaming on the tariffs, blaming on the tariffs. Yes, tariffs make some prices go up,
but
Speaker 5: they don't make all prices go up. So tariffs are not the source of inflation. They are the source
Speaker 7: of some economic pain, and they can be the source of higher prices to the extent that they reduce the supply of goods. If there's fewer goods coming into the country, then they could all sell at higher prices. And so that's not more money being created. That's fewer goods being supplied. So in that respect, but our imports have not slowed down.
Speaker 7: We're not importing less. And I'm going to get into that. We're still importing. We're just paying more for what we import and therefore running a bigger trade deficit. But the other excuse for inflation was AI. They're blaming AI.
for
Speaker 7: inflation, because of the demand that AI is injecting into the economy, all of the resources that are being consumed to build out all the infrastructure, the data centers, putting upward pressure on prices. So even though in the long run, AI is supposed to
Speaker 7: be a force to lower prices by increasing productivity. In the short run, it is pushing prices up. But the real reason that prices go up is not because of demand for resources coming from AI. It's the Fed.
Speaker 7: It's the Fed's balance sheet that continues to expand. It's money supply that continues to expand. It's credit that continues to expand because the Fed is too loose. The Fed has interest rates too low now, and they've been too low for many, many years. And the Fed had an opportunity to try to correct that, and they punted. What did they do? Walsh set up five task forces to study the problems, which...
He
Speaker 7: had plenty of time to study these problems before he became Fed chair, why he needs the task force, and why the task force is going to be any better than the Fed. I mean, don't we have all these smart guys already studying this? Haven't they been studying inflation for years or decades? What's setting up a new task force going to do? Absolutely nothing but buy time.
Speaker 7: Allow Walsh to delay, to do nothing while supposedly these task force are figuring out a solution to a problem that's obvious, but he can't acknowledge it because the politics of it are too bad. The problem is caused by too much government, too much government spending, too high deficits. And the solution is to reduce deficit spending, shrink the money supply, raise interest rates. But that's not possible.
Speaker 7: politically viable because of what would happen to the stock market what would happen to the real estate market what would happen to the economy so it's not going to happen but i think that the markets at least if they paid attention to what the fed is bluffing here if they're actually going to do it because remember
what's left of
Speaker 4: the fed's credibility is on the line here because at some
the Fed
Speaker 4: to follow through, because inflation is not going to come back down, even though we had a pullback in oil prices. That's already reversing. But prices for everything are going up. That hasn't stopped. Those pressures continue to build in the economy. And so at some point,
You
Speaker 4: can't just talk, you have to act, you have to do something. The Fed can't just talk about hiking rates, it's going to have to actually hike them. And if it doesn't, there goes what's left of the Fed's credibility. So the markets should be weaker. The stock markets should be a lot weaker right now with this threat, unless
Speaker 1: nobody believes it.
Speaker 1: But the gold traders believe it. I think that's the main reason that gold is still
Speaker 4: 4,000, 4,100. It's because of the expectation that the Fed is going to be hiking interest rates. That's why the dollar index is 101. The dollar rose based on the expectation that the Fed is going to be hiking interest rates. If it doesn't deliver these hikes, that amounts to a cut. In fact, it amounts to a big cut.
Speaker 4: Even if they do hike, it's a cut because they're not going to hike as much as inflation is rising. So real interest rates are going to fall. I've been hammering this point for months and months on this podcast. Investors don't seem to get it, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 4: What the Fed does on rates, because even if we get three 25 basis point rate hikes, that's 75 basis points. That's nothing. Inflation is going to be a lot higher than that above what had been anticipated. And so real rates are going to go down even if nominal rates go up. But the problem is we have so much debt.
The
Speaker 4: economy, the labor market, I went over how bad the jobs numbers were that we got on Thursday on my last podcast, but the labor market is weak. The economy is weak. The housing market is weak. And the last thing that, you know, they, the markets could survive.
Speaker 4: would be rate hikes. In fact, that's the main reason that the rate hikes were called off in the first place. That's the reason that when Powell was president, that they cut interest rates. It wasn't just to try to help reelect Biden or to elect Kamala Harris.
Speaker 4: It was because banks started to fail. It was because the economy was at risk because of the enormity of the amount of debt that we have. Our debt problem is getting worse. In fact, look at the trade deficits that just came out. We got the report on the June trade deficit.
Speaker 5: The unified trade deficit came up, the May deficit, and we had a huge increase.
Speaker 4: from the prior month 42 percent rise in the trade deficit
the prior month was
Speaker 1: 54.6 billion dollars and may was 77.6 billion now
the
Speaker 1: That was actually a little less than the markets expected. So the markets expected a huge increase and we got a huge increase. And that huge increase was driven both by a 3.2%
Speaker 4: drop in exports and a 3.3% rise in imports. So on both sides, it got worse. And in fact, if you just look at the
Speaker 1: goods trade deficit, merchandise,
which
Speaker 1: for the month of May, because we do have a surplus in services. But the goods deficit
was
Speaker 4: $106.5 billion. That is enormous. One of the worst goods deficits we've ever had. Trump was supposed to fix that with the tariffs. And once again, I said this from the
Speaker 5: beginning, that the tariffs would not work.
And
Speaker 5: they didn't work. They didn't work during Trump's first term and they're not
working during
Speaker 5: his second.
Speaker 4: During his first term, he campaigned on lowering the deficits, the trade deficits. Yet the trade deficits hit record highs during Trump's presidency.
Speaker 4: I predicted that would happen. I said the tariffs would not have an effect, that the trade deficit would keep getting worse because the tariffs did not attack the disease, they attacked the symptom. And by doing that, they let the disease get worse. The same thing happened this time. The tariffs did not result in a manufacturing renaissance. The manufacturing recession continues,
Speaker 4: during Trump's term and we'd be continued to get more and more dependent on foreign manufacturing. And by the way, where AI is going to make a big difference initially is going to be in services. A lot of the services that America now exports, a lot of our customers may no longer need those services.
Speaker 5: They may able to have those services, those functions fulfilled
Speaker 5: by AI and so if we don't have to perform services because foreign companies could use AI to do the services that American workers used to
Speaker 4: provide well the deficit is going to get a lot worse because our surplus in services is going to shrink and so is the employment in the service sector because a lot of jobs
Speaker 4: are a function of services that we export, not only services that we consume domestically, but our trade surplus in services. Well, if our trading partners can now use AI to perform services that Americans
used
Speaker 5: to perform, well, those Americans are out of work. Anyway, got one more commercial break. So stick around. Coming right back.
Talk to
Speaker 8: any manufacturer in this country right now, and you'll hear the same thing. The pressure is coming from every direction. Rising energy costs, a tight labor market, supply chains that are still fragile, and cyber threats that get worse every quarter. This isn't one problem you can solve and move on. Rockwell Automation just put out their 11th annual State of Smart Manufacturing report. They surveyed over 1,500 decision-makers across 17 countries
Speaker 8: and what they found is exactly what you'd expect if you've been paying attention. 90% of manufacturers say digital transformation isn't optional anymore. It's the price of staying competitive. But here's where it gets interesting. Only 43% of the data these companies collect is actually being used. The rest just sits there. That's enormous value left on the table.
Speaker 8: and nearly half of them, 46%, were hit by a cyber incident in just the past year. As factories get more connected, that risk lands directly on the balance sheet. If you run a manufacturing business or you invest in one, this report is worth your time. Download it for free at rok.auto/sosm. That's rok.auto/sosm.
Speaker 1: You know, one of the main reasons that we have such big budget deficits
is
Speaker 1: that politicians, you know, want to get elected and they want to give the public what they want. That is the inherent flaw in democracy. And it's the reason the founding fathers created America as a republic, not as a democracy. It's not like democracies didn't exist. The founders were very familiar
Speaker 1: With democracies and their history of failure and the experiment that they launched in the United States was self-government as a republic, hoping that we could avoid the pitfalls of democracy. We have democratic features of our republic, but in general, the purpose of the republic is to protect the minority from the majority. But the reason I was thinking
about it
Speaker 1: this is I was watching on CNBC and there was like a on-air debate going on between this Steve Leisman who is the senior economics reporter and Rick Santelli in CNBC and I've known Rick for a long time and you know Rick's a good guy although I don't always agree with with Rick but I appreciate his enthusiasm and his sentiment and a lot of times
Speaker 1: He is right about things. And in this particular argument, he was right. Leisman is rarely,
Speaker 4: if ever, right. But what they were arguing about, and I didn't even see the whole thing. But at one point, Leisman said, well, you
Speaker 1: know, we have deficits because the public wants things, you know, the public wants health care. And therefore, according to Leisman, the government has to
Speaker 5: provide that health care because the public wants it.
Speaker 5: No,
Speaker 4: that is not the job of government. I went over that on my podcast before Independence Day, that the government is not there to provide
Speaker 5: us with the things that we want. The government is there to secure our liberties, to secure our rights. We don't have a right to health
Speaker 4: care because you can't have a right to something that imposes a responsibility on someone else.
Speaker 4: If I say I have a right to health care, well, then what doctor is my slave? I'm going to use the government to enforce slavery so that people will give me health care. No, you don't have the right to take anything away from somebody else. Rights exist on their own.
Speaker 4: The government secures your right to go out and pursue health care, meaning if I want to try to get health care, if I want to buy health care, the government has no right to interfere.
Although that's
Speaker 4: what our government does
all the
Speaker 4: time. They interfere with everything. There's all sorts of rules and regulations that limit my ability to buy the health care that I want because the FDA has to approve the drugs. And if the FDA doesn't approve it, I can't buy it.
Speaker 4: Even if I want it, see, we've got it all upside down. We actually destroy rights when the government says you can't choose. You can't buy what you want. You can't use the drugs that you want. But we're going to we're going to give you free health care. We're going to provide you money so long as you consume the health care that we deem is appropriate for you. But that is not the function of government.
yes
Speaker 4: people want health care they want a lot of things people want all kinds of stuff
that doesn't
Speaker 4: mean the government is supposed to provide it the government is supposed to stay out of the way because again the government doesn't have anything people say well the people want housing well how are they going to get housing from the government the government doesn't have any housing how
would the
Speaker 4: government get housing well they'd have to
Speaker 4: hire people to build houses where would they get the money they'd have to take it from the private sector so either they have to engage private contractors they have to take money from the taxpayer and then pay it out to a private builder but why interject the government if the public wants houses let the free market provide housing because that's how capitalism works people know gee
Speaker 7: people need houses right
If I
Speaker 7: make houses and sell them, I'll make some money. People need shelter. That's how capitalism functions. The capitalist identifies a need and he tries to satisfy that need because in the process, he can get rich. He can make money, but he only can make money if he satisfies needs efficiently and economically. He has to be able to satisfy needs
Speaker 7: by using fewer resources than the consumer would value them.
So I have to
Speaker 7: be able to use land, labor, and capital
to
Speaker 1: produce a home that somebody is going to want to buy because they're going to value the home at more than the cost of building it. The difference is the reward, which is the
Speaker 4: profit. I built a house at a price that...
Speaker 4: a consumer saw value. And obviously the house is
Speaker 5: a big example, but every product, clothing, food, whatever there is, as
a
Speaker 4: businessman, I am motivated by the needs and desires of my customers. If I can satisfy those needs and desires and I can do it efficiently, then I can make money. And so we have all these entrepreneurs trying to
Speaker 4: Give the public what the public wants. Now, not for free. Obviously, the public has to buy what it wants because it has to pay for the resources that are needed to produce what it wants. Because if nobody had to pay for anything, well, then there'd be nothing. Because the
Speaker 7: people who are my customers are also themselves producers. They're working. Either they have their own business or they're an employee for somebody else. They are collectively contributing.
Speaker 7: to all the economic output. And so they get to spend in proportion to what they helped produce. So their purchasing power comes from their own efforts, their own contributions. It just doesn't come out of thin
air. But
Speaker 7: when you try to interject the government, when you try to say, oh, the government is there to satisfy the demands that the people have, how are politicians gonna satisfy anything?
Speaker 7: There's no profit motive there. They're not running a business. All they can do is steal money from one person and give it to somebody else. And so when you assign government the task of satisfying the demands of consumers, they don't do it nearly as efficiently. So you waste resources. But more importantly, too, you destroy individual liberty.
You become
Speaker 7: destructive of the very means that government was created.
Speaker 7: Government is there to secure our rights and our liberties, not to give us stuff, but to make sure that we don't lose the stuff that we have, the stuff that we earn. You know, I was reading, you know, on X, you know, about the wealth tax and all this stuff.
Speaker 7: I was at either maybe Elizabeth Warren Post and she was, you know, she was talking about the big, beautiful bill and she was speaking critically of the big, beautiful bill.
And I
Speaker 7: agree with her. I was critical of the big, beautiful bill, but for the wrong reasons. Elizabeth Warren said that the big, beautiful bill was the rich robbing for the middle class and the poor because they got the lion's share of the tax cuts because more of the tax cuts went to the rich.
Speaker 7: Then to the poor, she considered it legalized theft as if the wealthy people keeping more of what they earn somehow constitutes theft. I
mean, think
Speaker 7: about where we've come. So if I want to keep my money, I've stolen it, the money that I earned, the property that I own, if I object to the government taking my property, then I'm a thief.
Speaker 7: No, no, it's thievery that I object to. The thieves are not the people who earn the money. The thieves are the people who wanna take the money. There's nothing wrong with wanting to keep what you earn, your property, that's human nature. That's the whole American system about private property, about not having your private property taken away from you. And just because the government has the rights to tax us
Speaker 7: They can't tax us to take our money and give it to somebody else. They can tax us for the general welfare of the country, not the specific welfare of an individual. They can tax us to cover the military and stuff like that, but they're not allowed to redistribute wealth. The Constitution was written specifically to prevent the government from redistributing wealth. But according to Elizabeth Warren, if you don't want your wealth redistributed, then you're stealing.
Speaker 7: Right. Anything that you don't let the government take from you is money that you stole. No, the thieves. Right. She never calls people on welfare thieves. You know, they're not stealing money. Of course, they're getting money that was stolen. They're the recipients of stolen money. But they voted for the thieves. They're the accomplices to the crime. They're the they're the thieves, not the people that earn the money. And by the way, how did they earn that money?
Speaker 7: they created businesses, they produce products, they provide services, they created jobs, they added a lot of value. And in exchange, they earn money. And the fact that they want to keep more of that money does not make them a thief. In fact, I was looking on my own X account. And again, if you're not following me on X, make a point and do that. I'm adding now about 100,000 followers a month, three to 4,000 a day. So the pace of followers has picked up
Speaker 7: recently which is which is good i'm that means i'm getting i'm getting my my message out there but somebody on that same thread
Speaker 1: somebody said
why is
Speaker 1: it that the rich are always trying to avoid taxes right they're like like only the rich try to avoid taxes everybody tries to avoid taxes so i answered this guy
Speaker 1: And I said the rich try to avoid taxes for the same reason the middle class and the poor try to avoid taxes. Nobody wants to pay taxes. It's not like the rich
are so
Speaker 1: greedy they don't want to pay taxes. First of all, they already pay high taxes. Most of the taxes, most of the income tax is paid by the rich. It's not like they're not already paying a lot. They're paying more than their fair share. But sure.
They
Speaker 1: don't want to pay taxes, but neither do the middle class. In fact, most of the tax evasion is the middle class. The rich don't have to evade taxes. They got loopholes that they can use, but they still end up
paying a
Speaker 1: lot of taxes. I think the biggest tax evaders, and not that I blame them, and I'm not upset at
people who
Speaker 1: are struggling, but it's the middle class. I mean, how many people who were working for tips reported all their tips, honestly?
Speaker 1: Now, you know, you don't have to pay tax on a certain amount of tips, but a lot of people work for tips. A lot of people work for cash. How many people in the underground economy are millionaires and billionaires? Zero, right? The people working in the underground economy, in the gig economy, are middle class, working poor. There's a lot of undeclared income in the underground economy. Why? Because they don't want to pay the taxes, right? A lot of transactions that are affected in cash.
The
Speaker 1: people who are earning that cash are not declaring all their income. And think about all of the phony deductions that people claim, all sorts of stuff, right? That they inflate the value of their charitable donations or their home offices or, you know, people do all sorts of things to cheat on their taxes. In fact, there is an old expression that the income tax created more cheaters than golf.
Speaker 1: Everybody is cheating on their income taxes. I mean, very few people probably are completely honest on their taxes. Maybe if you're a W-2 employee, you have no deductions. But even still, you may earn a little money on the side that you don't declare. Maybe you have some gambling winnings that you didn't declare. All this stuff, the IRS expects you to declare this stuff.
Speaker 1: But most people don't. They figure if it's cash, nobody knows. So it's not just rich people who want to keep their property. Everybody wants to keep their property. Everybody has a right. That's what makes us free. What makes a free person versus a slave? A slave does not own his economic output. It belongs to the master.
And even,
Speaker 1: you know, a serf, you could say, you know, is beholden to the Lord. But even serfs got to keep 75% of what they produced. That's more than the average American. And the average American is lower in status than a serf. Most Americans would have to aspire to raise to the level of a serf. But again, the difference between being a slave and being a free person is owning your own labor, owning the fruits of your labor.
Speaker 1: Well, if the government claims that it owns our labor and it just lets us keep what it feels we deserve, that basically everything belongs to the government and we just get to keep whatever it thinks that we should be allowed to have, then what? We're all slaves to the government, right? We're living on this gigantic plantation and every one of us is a slave.
Speaker 4: No, we own everything.
Speaker 4: our bodies we own our labor and that's why inherently an income tax is wrong just philosophically the government should not be able to tax your labor if you own your labor if
Speaker 1: you're a free person then you own the wages that you earn you are you you know whatever you earn by working is your property it belongs
Speaker 4: to you and it can't be taken
Speaker 4: by the government. And in fact, it wasn't taken until we had an income tax, right? We didn't start off with an income tax. Yes, we had some tariffs or some sales tax, but that's not the same
Speaker 1: thing, right? Because you have a choice. I go out and buy a product that's subject to a tax, I pay the tax. If I don't buy the product, I don't pay the tax, right? But if they're taking your
income
You
Speaker 1: have no choice. You need income because I need to live. I need to feed myself. I need to house myself. So I need an income. And when the government taxes your income, you basically are a slave of the government. What we really need is another revolution to emancipate all Americans from modern-day economic slavery. Anyway, I also wanted to follow up. Oh, one more point, too. Ironically,
Speaker 1: Again, with the big increase in the deficit spending, finally, the Doge Committee, the Department of Government Efficiency, a oxymoron, if ever there was one, was officially shut down. And again, I hate to say I told you so because I opened up this podcast with
an I
Speaker 1: told you so, but even during the campaign, even during the 2024 campaign, the
When
Speaker 1: everybody was excited about Doge and all the cuts that were going to happen and how we were going to have trillions of dollars of cuts. So we were
going to
Speaker 1: get rid of the deficit. I was saying from the beginning that this was all talk. Nothing was going to happen. Nothing was going to get cut. People didn't believe me. They were just accusing me of, you know, Trump derangement syndrome. And I was like, look, I've seen this before. I remember Ronald Reagan. I remember the Grace Commission.
Speaker 1: They made a big deal about it, and nothing came out of it. And if Ronald Reagan, a true fiscal
Speaker 4: conservative, wasn't able to get any waste, fraud, and abuse cut from the federal budget, what hope would Donald Trump, who isn't
even a
Speaker 4: conservative? He's a
Speaker 1: Nixonian. He's nothing like Ronald Reagan. In fact, J.D. Vance is a big fan of Richard Nixon, right? So Trump is a left-wing conservative.
Speaker 1: Republican. So if a big
Speaker 4: government, big spending, I mean, if a if a real Goldwater conservative like Ronald Reagan couldn't get anywhere with cutting spending, knowing that he wanted to cut it, Trump didn't care. Trump just used it as a campaign issue. He just knew that he would get votes of certain people by promising to get rid of waste, fraud and abuse. So it was all a show.
Speaker 4: It's just that Elon Musk never got the memo because he actually showed up in Washington as if he was actually there to cut spending. That's why they had that big rift, because Elon actually tried to do something, and that upset Trump because Trump didn't want to do anything. Because as I said from the beginning, all this waste, fraud, and abuse is not in there by accident. There is a constituency behind every dollar we waste, because every dollar we waste is
Speaker 4: going to somebody. Somebody is benefiting from that dollar. And if you try to
Speaker 5: take it away, there's going to be political consequences. So now we have officially closed the book on Doge. It doesn't even exist anymore. So that's another thing that I got right, unfortunately. No cuts to government spending. But also another thing I've been right on is
Speaker 4: strategy. And
Speaker 1: Bitcoin guys are completely in denial of
Speaker 1: I would imagine we're going to see a trap door open up once Bitcoin breaks below like 58,000 and just Katie bar the door. It's going to go. Bitcoiners are delusional right now or in denial about what's happening with strategy. They do not understand how important strategy has been to Bitcoin, to the whole ecosystem, the whole industry,
Speaker 4: because he has provided all of that buying, that strategy.
Not
Speaker 4: only put a floor beneath Bitcoin and kept it going up, but legitimized it in the eyes of the financial community. All this so-called innovation, all this digital credit that
he was
Speaker 4: building, a lot of this stuff, he
was the
Speaker 4: real backbone of crypto and it has broke. In fact, Strategy Sailor announced on Monday.
Speaker 4: another week of Bitcoin selling. In fact, strategy has now sold Bitcoin for two weeks in a row, not bought any, sold. They sold a total of 3,588 Bitcoin, $215 million worth sold. Now, remember, the markets, you know, had a hissy fit when he sold 32. Now he's sold over 100 times that many.
But
Speaker 4: this is just the tip of the iceberg. He's got over 840,000 left to sell. Michael's strategy has gone from the biggest Bitcoin buyer to the biggest seller. And by the way, he sold at an average price of about 60,000. The average person price was 75,000. He lost $15,000 per Bitcoin on the 3,588. So that's a huge loss.
Speaker 4: Uh, that strategy booked real loss. I guess now they could write it off on their taxes, but this is very significant and it's not just, um, that he's not buying or that he's selling. It's the psychology. Yes,
all this
Speaker 4: buying is not there from strategy and strategy is selling and they probably won't sell as well.
Speaker 4: much as they were buying initially eventually they're going to sell a lot more eventually it's all going to get
Speaker 1: sold who knows at what price but he's going to try to gradually you know lower his exposure to raise his cash so he can keep on paying the dividends but look at what's going on with these strategies look at where so um micro strategy common stock closed at 93 87
and
Speaker 1: A little bit off the lows, but
Speaker 4: more important is the stretch price. You got to watch that because that really gives you an indication of the confidence in the market. Stretch is at 86. He just hiked the dividend to 12%, yet the shares are trading at 86, nowhere near 100, which means that more dividend hikes are coming. But more significantly, it shows that the investors have lost confidence.
In
Speaker 4: Bitcoin, they don't even believe that Bitcoin can deliver a 12% yield to stretch shareholders. That's why it's trading at 86. So this whole belief system is imploding. Wall Street is falling out of love with Bitcoin. The game is over and the market is telling you that. The confidence is not there anymore, right? The story is over, right? All the hype is...
Speaker 4: Didn't pan out or whatever panned out has already panned. And now it's just about the last man out. The last guy at the party, turn off the lights. So it is over. The story has played out. The Wall Street money is going to leave.
Speaker 4: All these strategy, all these, you know, Bitcoin treasury copycat companies, their whole business model has now been exposed
as a
Speaker 4: farce. So they're going to be winding down all of the speculators who took a shot at Bitcoin by buying Bitcoin ETFs. They're going to sell.
Speaker 4: The upside is gone out of Bitcoin. All the hype turned out to be just hype. Exactly what I said. Now, yes, the bubble got a hell of a lot bigger than I ever imagined 15 years ago or so when I first started talking about it. But over the last five years, they have not been able to push the market higher despite all the hype. In fact, Donald Trump came out,
Speaker 5: he was asked,
Speaker 5: Oh, and I wanted to mention Trump accounts. I totally forgot about these Trump accounts. But he was asked in an interview on the Trump accounts if he would consider allowing Trump accounts to invest in Bitcoin, which would be a complete disaster. And his response was, you know, I've become a big crypto guy. And so that kind of
Speaker 2: rallied the market. Yes, he is a big crypto guy because he made billions ripping people off using crypto. Crypto has been very, very good to Donald Trump.
But it
Speaker 2: hasn't been very
Speaker 1: good to the people who bought what Trump sold. In fact, the vast majority of the money that Trump made was selling overpriced tokens or meme coins or licensing meme coins or selling overpriced shares of companies that were somehow related to crypto to the public.
Speaker 1: That's, you know, Trump made money off of crypto by conning people using crypto. That's why
Speaker 4: he's a big crypto guy, not because he actually believes it's going to work. It worked great for him. It worked great for his family because they were able to extract all kinds of wealth from the public. Trump, when he made his $2.2 billion last year, he didn't make money creating wealth.
He
Speaker 4: made money siphoning wealth off of other people. He didn't create real value. He didn't grow a real business that produced products that people bought or services. No, Trump made his money because other people lost theirs. It was a transfer from the people who
bought to
Speaker 4: Trump who sold.
But
Speaker 4: I wanted to finally comment on these Trump accounts because I actually meant to do that earlier because the Trump accounts officially started trading this week. In fact, Donald Trump rang the opening bell from the White House, never been done before. Simultaneously, I think New York Stock Exchange is an adjunct. He rang the bell and he's making a big deal about how this is great for our kids and the young people. If Trump gave us two comments
Speaker 4: clicks about the young people he would cut government spending talking about giving them a thousand dollars because that's what they get right the government gives everybody a thousand dollars where do they get that money they have to borrow it so the same people that get the thousand dollars to put in the stock market get the bill for the thousand dollars added to the national debt that they have to repay
right
They
Speaker 4: have to pay the interest on it. They have to repay the principal. And now they got money to invest in an overpriced U.S. stock market. Now, yes, people can make contributions. The only contributions may come from employers because they can actually deduct what they put into an employee's Trump account
Speaker 1: for their kid. And it's not taxable income to the employer.
the
Speaker 1: worker. So
I do
Speaker 1: believe that you will see some money going into these
Speaker 4: Trump accounts in lieu of compensation. But what that means is the government will collect less in taxes. So all of the money that's likely to go into these Trump accounts or the vast majority of it is going to be at the expense of a bigger deficit and a larger national debt that the very people who the Trump accounts are supposed to help
are
Speaker 4: going to be inheriting. Look, the best thing that Trump could do for the young people is to forget about these Trump accounts, right? This is all form over substance. To do something substantial, cut government spending, cut Social Security, cut Medicare. This is what's killing young people, having to pay these high payroll taxes. Give them some relief there.
And
Speaker 4: then they had plenty of money to invest and spend. These gimmicks simply allow the problems to get worse. And Trump can pretend he's done something. Oh, look at this good thing. And now he's got his name on these accounts, right? So now even though he's not going to be president anymore, the Trump accounts will still exist, just like the airport in Palm Beach is now Trump International or whatever. He's trying to put his name everywhere.
Speaker 4: But what he really should be doing is trying to do what career politicians couldn't do, what people elected him to do, which is make America great again by not being a politician, by being a real leader, by being a statesman, by having the guts to do what career politicians couldn't do. But Trump is proving that he's a better politician than anybody, right? Because he is doing all things for all people and doesn't cut
Speaker 1: anything.
You
Speaker 1: know, massive increases in government spending, massive increases in the debt. Yet he claims that, you know, we're doing something for the young people who are being sacrificed. They are being
Speaker 4: burdened. Who does he think is going to repay this debt? If you care about posterity, you don't want to leave them with a pile of debt.
Speaker 4: this generation should be paying for what
Speaker 1: it needs, not passing the bill to its children and its grandchildren. Now, ultimately, of course, the bill is so great that we're going to end up paying most of it through inflation because our grandkids aren't going
to stick
Speaker 1: around to pay it. We're going to end up destroying it through inflation. And so
Speaker 1: that this generation is going to get stuck with the bill through runaway inflation because the young people, you know, they could always leave. You know, it's a big world. There's a lot of other places that people could go. They don't have to stay here to pay off our debts. They could leave and allow us to experience the massive inflation and deal with the consequences of our debt ourselves.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's it for today's podcast. Again, don't forget to subscribe to my YouTube channel. If you're watching this on my YouTube channel, make sure and subscribe to it. If you're just listening on SHIFT Radio, you can't really subscribe to that, but you can go to YouTube and you can subscribe. And as I mentioned earlier, follow me on X. Encourage your friends to follow me.
Speaker 1: My goal this year is to hit 2 million followers based on the way that I've been accumulating them recently. I think I'm going to get there. But with your help, I'll definitely get there. Bye for now.